KATE EFIMOVA

JavaScript and Java developer

Email: kate.efimova0@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/Kefimochi Twitter: https://twitter.com/kefimochi

Cell: (925) 326-8049

SUMMARY

Junior software engineer who has been practicing software development since 2016. Focuses on pleasant user experience while also considering the time and space complexity involved in building a product. Knows Big O notation and how to use it in order to provide memorable user experience.

Languages/Experience

- CSS/SCSS
- HTML
- JavaScript
- Photoshop
- Java
- C++

Took participation in:

- freeCodeCamp 466 challenges
- Several JavaScript 30 challenges
- My own MDN search browser extension

Classes taken

- Beginning C++, grade received: A
- Intermediate C++, grade received: A
- Data Abstract & Structures in Java, grade received: A
- Advanced Java, current grade: A

QUALIFICATIONS

Frontend Development

- Passionate about implementing intuitive design for users to enjoy.
- Cares about what matters most to the users, such as responsive web-design, fast animations with no lags, short page loading time and much more.

Fast Learner

- Grasped Java concepts in just three days after being familiar with C++ in order to take Data Abstract and Structures class.
- Dramatically increased the knowledge of English after moving from Russia to the United States. Hands on experience and diving deep into concepts is the best way to learn for me personally.
- Reading tech articles and listening to podcasts everyday in order to enhance understanding of the concepts.

Team Leader

- Took leadership role in every presentation project that was given in Middle College, which is a special program that allows high school students to take all college classes.
- Can easily find some common ground with every member of a team in order to motivate them to get the work done well together.

EXPERIENCE

MDN Search Extension

(2019-present)

Had an idea of making life of software engineers easier by creating MDN Search Extension, which would allow users to enter what they want to find and the extension would redirect them right away to the page they were looking for.

Currently in progress, but there is already version 1 prototype available on CodePen

De Anza Classes (2017-present)

Joined Middle College at 2017 due to being attracted of getting more opportunities to learn computer science. Participated in the program for two years, while also enriching knowledge in general fields like psychology and art, as well as enhancing coding skills. Got together well with other thirty students and quickly created a community of three other people with similar interest in coding around me. Together, we would help each other inside and outside of computer science classes.

- Currently have Cumulative(Unweighted) 3.854 GPA at Homestead High School
- Received 143 quality points at De Anza college and accumulated 3.95 GPA

Independent Web Development

(2016-present)

Developed various web pages according to the tutorials on the internet written by professionals in the field, as well as discovered common coding practices. Quickly grasped concepts of how well-developed web design looks like and tried implementing it on my own. Took a part in JavaScript 30, read more than a hundred articles on Medium, and listened to around 70-80 hours of tech-related podcasts. Build many features that can be used on websites

- Completed 466 freeCodeCamp challenges
- Personalized every JavaScript 30 challenge in order to try imitating real-world projects

Photoshop Designer

(2011-2016)

Used acquired Photoshop skills in order to produce web designs and avatars for people on beon.ru. Created an organized group with the co-founder where we would sell designs. The group quickly became popular for the quality of products that were made by people involved. For a year remained determined to run the group after which the popularity of Beon fell, which caused group members to slowly disappear.

- Sold a variety of designs to people who continued to "wear" my works on their blog pages for at least 3-4 months each
- Gained valuable experience of how to remain determined since each design took around 5-6 hours to make, while a video-avatar could accumulate up to 12-13 hours of work due to frame-by-frame edition.